On app launch, I know that you're probably tired of seeing the dummy data and
needing to hit the refresh button for real data every single time.
I'm going to show you how to display the data using the current settings each
time the activity is loaded. In forecast fragment,
we just refactored the code so that when the refresh button is selected,
we call this helper method, updateWeather. Now that it's in a helper method,
we can also call it from the onStart method. We over write onStart so
that the refresh happens whenever the fragment starts.
This will cause the weather data to appear. We'll learn all about on start, and
the rest of the android life cycle in the next lesson. At this point,
we can also remove all the fake data that we had in the onCreateView method.
Then we pass in an empty array list to the ArrayAdapter. Now we can test this.
We need to make sure that this is the first app launch and
that it wasn't already running,. So if it's already running, kill it.
And then tap to open the app,
and then you should see the actual weather data immediately. Under settings we
can change the location to be the pairs postal code. We hit OK, and
then return to the main list, and then we see that the weather data has updated.